Guide to the Mitchell-Tiffany Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Returning to America in comparatively good health in September, 1846, Mitchell began writing for the Morning Courier and New York Enquirer under the pseudonym "Ik Marvel." In New York he also studied law, (under the guidance of John Osborne Sargent), but his principal interest continued to be his literary work. In 1847 he published his first book, Fresh Gleanings, which was a record of his European travels. In June, 1848, he went to Paris and wrote a series of 30 letters for the Courier and Enquirer on the Revolution of 1848. His second book, The Battle Summer (1850), written after his return to America, dealt with events leading up to the revolution. A projected sequel was never written. During 1850 he edited the Lorgnette, a journal designed to satirize the follies of New York society. His Reveries of a Bachelor was a popular success and was followed in 1851 by Dream Life. Beginning in 1868, he edited the journal Hearth and Home, with Harriet Beecher Stowe.
Donald Grant Mitchell contributed to the leading American periodicals from 1842 to 1897. His writings also include: Fudge Doings (1855); My Farm of Edgewood (1863); Seven Stories (1864); Wet Days at Edgewood (1865); Doctor Johns (1866); Rural Studies (1867, republished as Out-of-Town Places, 1884); About Old Story Tellers (1877); Woodbridge Record (1883); Daniel Tyler (1883); Bound Together (1884); English Lands, Letters and Kings (4 vols. 1889-1897); and American Lands and Letters (2 vols. 1897-1899). The Edgewood edition of his works in fifteen volumes was published in 1907.
On May 31, 1853, Donald Grant Mitchell married Mary Frances Pringle, of Charleston, South Carolina. He then served as the United States Consul in Venice until his resignation in February 1854, when he moved to Paris. Mitchell returned to the United States in May, 1855, and purchased a two hundred acre farm, later increased to 360 acres, near New Haven, Connecticut. He called this farm "Edgewood." His earlier interests in farming grew to include town and park planning, and "Edgewood" became the example of his sense of beauty to which his series of Edgewood books were devoted. In 1904 the New England Association of Park Superintendants awarded Mitchell a silver cup in recognition that he had "laid the foundation for scientific and beautiful park building throughout this country." Included in the collection is his proposal for the lay-out of East Rock Park in New Haven. Donald Grant Mitchell died at Edgewood on December 15, 1908.
Louis Mitchell was born November 7, 1826, in New London, Connecticut, the son of the Reverend Alfred Mitchell and Lucretia M. (Woodbridge) Mitchell. He suffered from serious physical disabilities as a result of a childhood illness which was poorly treated. After the death of his mother in 1839, he and his younger brother Alfred continued their education under the guardianship of General William Williams. At the outbreak of the Civil War Alfred was commissioned as a captain in the Thirteenth Connecticut Regiment, and although Louis was exempted from service because of his physical disabilities, he took passage as ship companion on the vessel which transported the Thirteenth Regiment to New Orleans. He collected information on the Connecticut regiments which he supplied to those who later compiled records. He also collected the material for a proposed genealogy of the Woodbridge family, but died before he was able to complete the project. The notes which he left were used by Donald Grant Mitchell to complete the genealogy, which was published in 1883 as the Woodbridge Record. Louis Mitchell lived in Norwich with his cousin, Mrs. Levi Hart Goddard, and in New London with the family of his brother Alfred Mitchell. He died on July 15, 1881, at the age of 54.
Stephen Mix Mitchell was born in Wethersfield, Connecticut on December 9, 1743, the only child of James Mitchell and his second wife Rebecca, daughter of Rev. Stephen and Mary (Stoddard) Mix. James Mitchell had emigrated from Paisley, Scotland, and settled in Wethersfield, Connecticut. Stephen Mix Mitchell's mother, who was a first cousin of Jonathan Edwards, died while he was an infant. After his graduation from Yale College in 1763, Stephen Mitchell received a Berkeley Scholarship and in September, 1766, began a three year term as tutor in the college. At the same time he pursued a law degree under the direction of the Hon. Jared Ingersoll. On August 2, 1769, he married Hannah Grant, daughter of Donald Grant, an emigrant from Inverness, Scotland, to Newtown, Connecticut.
Stephen Mix Mitchell was admitted to the Fairfield County bar in 1770, and settled in Newtown, but in 1772 moved to Wethersfield, where he continued in practice for about seven years. He began his public career as a Representative in the General Assembly of the State in October, 1778, and in the following May he accepted the office of Associate Judge of the Hartford County Court. He was elected as a delegate to the Continental Congress in 1783, 1785, and 1787 and lived to be the last surviving member of the Old Congress, with the exception of President James Madison. Mitchell continued as Representative in the General Assembly (serving one term as clerk) until his transfer to the upper house of the legislature in 1784. He was reelected to the House of Assistants for seven more years (1785, 1787, 1792) and was then chosen to fill the unexpired term of the late Honorable Roger Sherman as United States Senator, serving from December, 1793, to March, 1795. In May, 1790, he became Presiding Judge of the Hartford County Court, until his transfer to the Superior Court in October, 1795. Mitchell became Chief Justice of the State in May, 1807, retiring in 1814. He was a presidential elector in 1805, and in 1807 Yale College conferred on him the honorary degree of Doctor of Laws. In 1788 Mitchell served as a member of the State Convention which ratified the Constitution of the United States and in 1818 as a member of the State Constitutional Convention.
Stephen Mix Mitchell died in Wethersfield on September 30, 1835, at the age of 93. His wife, Hannah (Grant) Mitchell, died on February 14, 1830, at the age of 81. Their marriage produced eleven children, of whom Walter Mitchell (1777-1849) and the Rev. Alfred Mitchell (1790-1831) are represented in the collection.
Walter Mitchell, the third son of the Honorable Stephen Mix Mitchell, was born in Wethersfield on October 7, 1777. He became a lawyer and practiced for many years in Hartford. He also served as a judge of the Hartford County Court from 1838 to 1840. He never married and died in Hartford on July 29, 1849, at the age of 72.
Charles Lewis Tiffany, the son of Comfort and Chloe (Draper) Tiffany, was born in Killingly, Connecticut, on February 15, 1812, a descendant of Humphrey Tiffany who settled in the Massachusetts Bay Colony around 1600. As a boy he attended district schools and then spent two years at an academy in Plainfield, Connecticut. At the age of fifteen he managed a general store for his father, and when his father's cotton manufacturing mill became prosperous, he entered the business. In 1837 he and John B. Young moved to New York and opened a stationery and notion shop. The business grew, and with the retirement of Young and Ellis, a third partner, from the firm, it was reorganized in 1853 as Tiffany and Company. By this time it had become primarily a jewelry business.
Tiffany and Company became the foremost of American jewelers, with more than twenty foreign monarchs among its customers. In addition to establishing Tiffany and Company, Charles Tiffany was one of the founders of the New York Society of Fine Arts, a patron of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, and a member of the National Academy of Design. France made him a Chevalier of the Legion of Honor (1878) and the Czar of Russia conferred on him the medal Praemia Digno.
Charles Tiffany married Harriet Olivia Avery Young, the sister of his first partner, on November 30, 1841. Six children were born of the marriage: Charles Lewis, born October 7, 1842, died in infancy; Annie Olivia, born November 27, 1844, later married Alfred Mitchell (1832-1911); Louis Comfort, born February 18, 1848, became the founder, president and director of the Tiffany Glass Company; Louise Harriet, born December 18, 1856; Henry Charles, born September 1, 1858, who also died in infancy; and Burnett Young, born April 12, 1860. Harriet (Young) Tiffany died November 6, 1897, in Yonkers, New York, and Charles Tiffany died February 18, 1902, in New York, at the age of 90.
Louis Comfort Tiffany was born in New York City on February 18, 1848, the son of Charles Lewis and Harriet Olivia A. (Young) Tiffany. His formal education took him through secondary school, after which he studied art, first with George Inness and Samuel Colman, and later under Leon Bailly in Paris. He was accepted as an associate of the National Academy of Design in 1871.
On May 15, 1872, he married Mary Woodbridge Goddard, a cousin of Alfred Mitchell, whom, she referred to affectionately as "Uncle Alf." Four children were born of the marriage: Mary Woodbridge, born April 3, 1873, was known as "May May;" Charles Louis, born December 9, 1874, died in infancy; Charles Lewis II, born January 7, 1878, later became a vice president of Tiffany and Company; and Hilda Goddard, born August 24, 1879. Mary (Goddard) Tiffany died on January 22, 1884. His second marriage, to, Louise Wakeman Knox, took place on November 9, 1886. Four children were born of the marriage: Louise Comfort, born September 24, 1887; Julia DeForest, born September 24, 1887; Annie Olivia, born December 29, 1888, who died as a young child; and Dorothy Trimble, born October 11, 1891. Louise (Knox) Tiffany died in 1904.
In 1877 Louis Tiffany and other artists, including Wyatt Eaton, John La Farge and Augustus Saint-Gaudens, who felt that the National Academy of Design was too narrow and unprogressive, organized the Society of American Artists. In 1875 Tiffany began experimenting with stained glass and in 1878 established a glass-making plant of his own. He invented a process of his own for making glass, giving it the name Favrile glass. Popularly known as "Tiffany" glass, it brought him his greatest popular reputation. Between 1893 and 1926 Tiffany was awarded numerous prizes and medals, among them the Grand Prix and a gold medal at the Paris Exposition of 1900. He was a Chevalier of the Legion of Honor and honorary member of the Imperial Society of Fine Arts of Tokyo and of the Société Nationale des Beaux Arts of Paris. In 1919 he established the Louis Comfort Tiffany Foundation for art students. He was a vice president and director of both Tiffany and Company jewelers and Tiffany and Company Safe Deposit Company. Louis Comfort Tiffany died in New York City on January 17, 1933, at the age of 84.
In addition to materials found in the collection, the following sources were used in the preparation of the biographical notes.
Dexter, Franklin Bowditch. Biographical Sketches of the Graduates of Yale College with Annals of the College History. New York: Henry Holt and Company, 1907.
Dunn, Waldo H. The Life of Donald Grant Mitchell. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1922.
Malone, Dumas, ed. Dictionary of American Biography. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1936.
[underline]. National Cyclopaedia of American Biography. James T. White and Co. 1897. 1950.
Perkins, Mary E. Chronicles of a Connecticut Farm, 1769-1905. Privately printed, 1905.
Purtell, Joseph. The Tiffany Touch. New York: Random House, 1971.
Tiffany, Nelson Otis. The Tiffanys of America. 1901.
For a chart outlining the genealogical relations of the Mitchell-Tiffany family, please consult the Genealogical Chart.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Families; Parks -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Students; Women -- Education; World War, 1914-1918; Europe; Great Britain; United States -- Social life and customs; Diaries; Sermons; Clergy; Bingham, Alfreda Mitchell, 1874-1914; Jeans, Charly Tiffany Mitchell, 1877-1934; Jeans, James, 1877-1946; Lusk, Graham, 1866-1932; Mitchell, Alfred, 1790-1831; Mitchell, Alfred, 1832-; Mitchell, Annie Olivia Tiffany, 1844-1937; Mitchell, Donald Grant, 1822-1908; Mitchell, Louis, 1826-1881; Mitchell, Lucretia Mumford Woodbridge, 1794-1839; Mitchell, Stephen Mix, 1818-1839; Mitchell, Walter, 1777-1849; Tiffany, Charles Lewis, 1812-1902; Tiffany, Louis Comfort, 1848-1933; Tiffany, May Goddard, 1846-1884; Williams, William; Young, Lydia B., d. 1894; Mitchell family; Tiffany family; Bryn Mawr College; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1854
- CORRESPONDENCE OF ALFRED AND ANNIE O. MITCHELL, 1861-1932; Series I; 3.5 linear feet (8 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Select Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by the name of the author. Within each folder, the letters are arranged chronologically. The individuals represented in this section are primarily family members or close friends, some of whom Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell apparently met during her school days.
  The second section, General Correspondence, is arranged chronologically and contains general and less substantive letters as well as a few letters from unidentified individuals.
  Letters of a purely financial or legal nature will be found in Series II. A few letters addressed to Alfred Mitchell dealing with family history and the correspondence received by other family members will be found in Series V.
  - Select Correspondence
    - Almy, Amelia, 1864, 1866, 1886, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Arnold, Harold Sears, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Backus, William H. [cousin of Annie O.(Tiffany) Mitchell], 1864-1865 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bingham, Alfred Mitchell (b. 1905) [grandson of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell], 1911-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bingham, Alfreda (Mitchell) (1874-1967) [daughter of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell]
      - 1887 - 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5-18)
      - 1921 - 1925 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
      - 1926 - 1932, undated (Box 2, Folder 21-23)
    - Bingham,:Brewster (b.1908) [grandson of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell], 1921-1932, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bingham, Charles Tiffany (b. 1906) [grandson of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell], 1922-1927 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Bingham, Hiram III (1875-1956) [son-in-law of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell]
      - 1902 - 1931 (Box 2, Folder 26-28)
    - Bingham, Hiram IV (b. 1903) [grandson of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell], 1909-1932 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Bingham, Woodbridge (b. 1901) [grandson of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell], 1909-1927 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Bingham, Ursula (Griswold) [wife of Woodbridge Bingham], 1927 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Bingham, Mitchell (b. 1910) Bingham, Jonathan Brewster (b. 1914) [grandsons of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell], 1918, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Bleeker, Libbie, 1861-1865, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Cole, Emily, 1861-1863, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Davenport, Millie, 1863-1866 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - de Forest, Julia B., 1886 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Fairchild, Davie, 1922, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Flachsbart, Berna and K., 1909-1928 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Gilder, Comfort (Tiffany) (1887-?) [daughter of Louis C. Tiffany and niece of Annie O.(Tiffany) Mitchell], 1894-1898, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Gilder, Rodman [husband of Comfort (Tiffany) Gilder], 1929 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Goddard, Henry P., 1863-1867 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Gray, Henry Peters, Sr. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Gray., Henry Peters, Jr., 1866-1867 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Hoffman, Mary Colden, 1861-1864, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Hoffman, Virginia, 1862-1866, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Huntington, Mary L., 1863-1866 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Hyde, Nannie J., 1864, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Jeans, Charly Tiffany (Mitchell) (1877-1934) [daughter of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell]
      - 1888 - 1895 January - Dec, undated (Box 3, Folder 45-49)
      - 1896 - 1904 (Box 3, Folder 50-54)
      - 1907 - 1908 (Box 3, Folder 55-56)
      - 1909 January - Dec, undated (Box 4, Folder 57-58)
      - 1910 - 1918 January - June (Box 4, Folder 59-68)
      - 1918 - 1932 (Box 5, Folder 69-76)
    - Fragments, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Jeans, James H. (1877-1946) [known as "Fred," son-in-law of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell]
      - 1906 - 1932, undated (Box 5, Folder 78-82)
    - Jeans, Olivia [grandaughter of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell, 1915-1932, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Kingsland, D. (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Kingsland, Emile, 1863-1865 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Lee, Fanny, 1861-1862 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Lee, Libby, 1861-1863, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Lusk, Graham [husband of May (Tiffany) Lusk], 1914 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Lusk, Louise and William [children of May (Tiffany) Lusk], 1909 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Lusk, May (Tiffany) [daughter of Louis C. Tiffany and niece of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell] (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - McClure, Nellie, 1864-1865 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Mitchell, Alfred (1832-1911) [husband of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell]
      - 1867 - 1869, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 89)
      - 1895, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 90)
      - n. d. (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Mitchell, Annie O. (Tiffany) (1844-1937) [wife of Alfred Mitchell], 1869? (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Mitchell, Donald Grant (1822-1908) [brother of Alfred Mitchell; "Ik Marvel")
      - 1885 - 1908, undated (Box 6, Folder 93-95)
    - Mitchell, Donald Grant [nephew of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell], 1905-1927 (Box 6, Folder 96)
      General
      See also: box 9, folder 1
    - Mitchell, Elizabeth [niece of Alfred and Annie Mitchell], 1883-1887, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Mitchell, Louis (1826-1881) [brother of Alfred Mitchell], 1868-1881 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - Nevins, Anna, 1867, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - Nevins, Cornelia L., 1897-1898 (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Perkins, Julia [cousin of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell], 1923 (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Perkins, Lillie, 1865-1867, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - Perkins, Mary [cousin of Alfred and Annie Mitchell], 1904, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Piatt, Julia (Goddard) [cousin of Alfred Mitchell]
      - 1864 - 1893 (Box 6, Folder 104)
      - 1901 - 1908 (Box 6, Folder 105-106)
      - 1915, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Porter, Mary and Annie, 1862-1866, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Smilie, James D., 1870 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Thorne, Robert
    - Thorne, Ruth B., 1907 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Tiffany, Burnett Y. (1860-?) [brother of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell], 1869-1870, 1927, undated (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Tiffany, Charles Lewis (1812-1902) Tiffany, Harriet Olivia A. (Young) (1813-?) [parents of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell]
      - 1857 - 1869 (Box 6, Folder 112-113)
      - 1881 - 1885 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      - 1886 - 1899, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 115)
    - Tiffany, Charles L. II (1878-?) [son of Louis C. Tiffany and nephew of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell], 1920-1932 (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Tiffany, Henry [uncle of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell], 1863-1866, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - Tiffany, Julia (1887-?) [daughter of Louis C. Tiffany and niece of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell], 1894-1897 (Box 7, Folder 118)
    - Tiffany, Louis Comfort (1848-1933) [brother of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell], 1862-1920, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 119)
    - Tiffany, Louise (1856-?) [sister of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell], 1886, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - Tiffany, Louise Wakeman (Knox) (1851-?) [2nd wife of Louis C. Tiffany, sister-in-law of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell], 1886 (Box 7, Folder 121)
    - Tiffany, May (Goddard) (1846-1884) [wife of Louis C. Tiffany and sister-in-law of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell]
      - 1861? - 1868 January - Dec, undated, 1869-1883 (Box 7, Folder 122-128)
    - Trembly, Amy, 1863-1867, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 129)
    - Williams, William [guardian of Alfred Mitchell], 1853, 1877 (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Verdi, William F.
      See also: box 1, folder 2
    - Young, E. S. [aunt of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell], 1865-1866 (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - [Young,?] [grandmother of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell] (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - Young, Lydia B. [aunt of Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell] (?-1894)
      - 1862 (Box 8, Folder 132)
      - 1863 - 1869 (Box 8, Folder 133-136)
      - 1886 - 1887, n. d. (Box 8, Folder 137)
  - General Correspondence
    - Letters written by Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell, 1862-1874, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - Letters to Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell
      - 1857 - 1932, undated (Box 8, Folder 139-146)
    - Invitations, 1866-1934, n. d. (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - Letters received on the engagement of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell, 1871 (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Letters received on the death of Charles L. Tiffany, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - Letters received on the death of Alfred Mitchell, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 150)
- FINANCIAL, LEGAL AND HOUSEHOLD PAPERS OF ALFRED AND ANNIE O. MITCHELL, 1887-1935; Series II; 2 linear feet (6 boxes)
  Series II consists of financial statements, statements of receipts and disbursements, financial and legal correspondence, legal documents, stock-holders notices, stock certificates and various household accounts, receipts and memoranda. The items are arranged chronologically by type of material.
  - Wills of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell, 1895-1931 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Annie O. Mitchell Trust (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Trust agreement between Annie O. Mitchell and Charles L. Tiffany, Robert Thorne and Winthrop E. Dwight, Trustees, 1911 May 24 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Charles L. Tiffany, Robert Thorne and Winthrop E. Dwight, as Trustees… v. Annie O. Mitchell: account of the trustees to the Supreme Court of the State of New York for the period 1911 May 24 - 1930 Dec 23 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Charles L. Tiffany, Robert Thorne and Winthrop E. Dwight, as Trustees… v. Annie O. Mitchell: affidavit and final judgment, 1931 February 17 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Financial statements
      - 1911 - 1926 (Box 9, Folder 5-11)
      - 1930 - 1935 (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
    - Statements of receipts and disbursements
      - 1911 - 1932 (Box 10, Folder 14-26)
    - Last Will and Testament of Charles L. Tiffany, 1887 March 7 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, legal documents and financial statements relating to the estate of Charles L. Tiffany
      - 1902 - 1929 (Box 11, Folder 28-29)
    - Correspondence, legal documents and financial statements relating to the Burnett Y. Tiffany Trust, 1902-1906 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Legal documents relating to the Burnett Y. Tiffany Trust, 1906? (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence and legal documents relating to the Burnett Y. Tiffany Trust, 1907-1908 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Legal documents relating to the Burnett Y. Tiffany Trust, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence and legal documents relating to the Burnett Y. Tiffany Trust, 1910 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence relating to the Burnett Y. Tiffany Trust, 1911-1912 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence and legal documents relating to the Burnett Y. Tiffany Trust
      - 1923 - 1928 (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - 1931 - 1932, undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Financial statements of the Burnett Y. Tiffany Trust, 1919-1926 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Financial statements of the Louise H. Tiffany Trust, 1906-1909 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, memoranda and financial statements relating to the Annie O. Mitchell Trust for the benefit of Alfreda M. Bingham and Charly T. M. Jeans, 1917-1931, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence and legal documents relating to the Annie O. Mitchell Trust for the benefit of Olivia Jeans, 1925-1927 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Financial correspondence, memoranda, receipts, and promissory notes, 1902-1932, n. d. (Box 12, Folder 42)